A Guide to the Virginia Bureau of Insurance Reports of Defunct Companies, 1876-1906
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Bureau of Insurance Reports of Defunct Companies, 1876-1906
The Library of Virginia
24810
2 cu. ft. (4 boxes)
SCC
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by State Corporation Commission on February 20, 1958.
Biographical Information
The Bureau is organized into four divisions: financial regulation; life and health market regulation; property and casualty market regulation; and agent regulation and administration. The Bureau licenses, regulates, investigates and examines insurance companies, agencies and agents on behalf of the citizens of the Commonwealth of Virginia. The Bureau of Insurance also registers, examines and investigates (title) real estate settlement agents and agencies.
Scope and Content
Reports from defunct insurance companies operating in Virginia to the State Corporation Commission.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Reports of Defunct Companies
Contents List
- Bureau of Insurance Reports of Defunct Companies, 1876-1906., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 1-4)
  - Accession 24810, 1876-1906.
    This accession is arranged in alphabetical order.
    - Aetna Fire Insurance Company, 1889. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aetna Life Insurance Company, 1889. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alexandria Home Fire Insurance Company, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Bonding and Trust Company, 1896, 1898, 1900. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Bonding Company of Baltimore, 1902. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Casualty Insurance and Security Company, 1890. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Credit Indemnity Company, 1901. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Employees Liabilities Insurance Company, 1892. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Fire Insurance Company of New York, 1898. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Atlanta-Birmingham Fire Insurance Company of Atlanta, 1903. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Atlantic Trust and Deposit Company, 1902. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Steam Boiler Insurance Company, 1896. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Armstrong Fire Insurance Company, 1889. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Boston Marine Insurance Company, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - British and Foreign Marine Insurance Company, 1892. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Brooklyn Life Insurance Company, 1891. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Colonial Assurance Company of New York, 1896. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Colonial Fire Insurance Company of D.C., 1902. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Connecticut Fire Insurance Company, 1889. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Continental Insurance Company, 1889. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Delare Insurance Company, 1892. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dominion Fire Insurance Corporation, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Eastern Shore of Virginia Fire Insurance Company, Inc., 1906. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Eureka Life Insurance Company, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Fidelity Fire Insurance Company of New York, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Firemen's Insurance Company, 1899. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Galilean Fishermen's Relief Association, 1894. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - General Accident Insurance Company, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - General Marine Insurance Company, 1893. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - German American Fire and Marine Lloyds of New York, 1895. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - German Insurance Company, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - German National Insurance Company, 1906. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Germana Life Insurance Company, 1890. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Glen Falls Fire Insurance Company, 1885. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Globe and Rutgers Fire Insurance Company, 1906. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Greensboro Life Insurance Company, 1906. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Greenwich Insurance Company, 1893-1896. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Guarantee and Accident--Lloyds, 1892. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Guarantee Company of North America, 1903. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Guarantors of Pennsylvania, 1894. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Guarantors of Pennsylvania, 1897. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Guardian Fire and Life Insurance Company, 1889-1893. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Hall and Henshaw Fire Underwriters, 1897. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Hartford Life Insurance Company, 1899. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Hartford Steam Boiler Inspection and Insurance Company, 1890. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Home Fire Insurance Corporation of Virginia, 1905. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Homestead Fire Insurance Corporation, 1905. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Howard Fire Insurance Company of Baltimore, 1898. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Imperial Fire Lloyds of New York, 1895. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Imperial Insurance Company, 1900. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Indemnity Insurance Company of West Virginia, 1903. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Independent Plate Glass Underwriters, 1904. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Interstate Casualty Company of New York, 1893. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Interstate Fire Insurance Company, Inc., 1906. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Jefferson Fire Insurance Company of Philadelphia, 1906. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Lancashire Insurance Company of Great Britain, 1892. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Law Union and Crown Insurance Company of London, England, 1903-1906. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Lion Fire Insurance Company, 1881-1901. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Magdeburg Fire Insurance Company, 1897. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Manchester Fire Assurance Company of England, 1896. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Manhattan Fire of New York, 1900. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Manhattan Fire Insurance Company (nee Mutual Fire Insurance Company of New York), 1897. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Manhattan Life Insurance Company, 1893. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Merchants and Manufacturers Fire Insurance Company, 1896. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Mutual Aid Association of Virginia, 1903. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - National Fire Insurance Company of Baltimore, Maryland, 1895. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - National Fire Insurance Company, 1889. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - National Indemnity and Insurance Company, 1899. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - National Insurance Company of Virginia, Inc., 1905. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - New Amsterdam Casualty Company of New York, 1900. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Old Dominion Beneficial Association of Richmond, Virginia, 1903. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Orient Fire Insurance Company of Hartford, Connecticut, 1887. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Palatine Insurance Company, 1899. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Penn Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1888. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Pennsylvania Fire Insurance Company, 1908. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Peoples Mutual Protective Association, 1904. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Phenix Fire Insurance Company, 1895. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Philadelphia Life Insurance Company, 1906. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Phoenix Assurance Company of London and New York, 1898. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Phoenix Insurance Company of Hartford, Connecticut, 1903. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Phoenix Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1893. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Provident Life and Trust Company of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1904. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Provident Savings and Life Assurance Company, 1889. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Prudential Fire Insurance Company, 1902. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Prudential Insurance Company of America, 1900. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Queen Insurance Company of America, 1891. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Queen Insurance Company of New York, 1891. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Republic Fire Insurance Company, Inc., 1905. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Security Life and Annuity Company of America, 1902. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Security Trust and Life Insurance Company, 1897. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Southern Fire Insurance Company, 1905. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Southern Savings Life and Accident Insurance Company, Inc., 1906. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Southern Underwriters of Greensboro, NC, 1903. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Southwestern Life Insurance Company, 1905. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Springfield Fire and Marine Insurance Company, 1905. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Standard Accident and Life, 1895. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - State Life Insurance Company, 1904. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - State Mutual Life and Annuity Association, 1906. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Stonewall Insurance Company, Inc., 1906. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - The Sun Life Assurance Company, 1895. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Thames and Mercy Marine Insurance Company, 1899. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Traders Insurance Company, 1904. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Underwriters of the New York and Chicago Lloyds of New York City, 1895. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Underwriters of the South and North American Lloyds, 1895. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Union Assurance Society of London, 1897. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Union Casualty and Surety Company, 1903. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - United Fire Insurance Company of Baltimore, Maryland, 1899. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - United Security Life Insurance and Trust Company of Pennsylvania, 1898. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - United States Fidelity and Guaranty Company, 1906. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Trust Company, 1894. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Life and Accident Insurance Company, Inc., 1905. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Washington Life Insurance Company, 1880. (Box 4, Folder 5)